Guide to the Budget Priorities Commission Task Force Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Budget Priorities Commission Task Force records
1974-1976
SC0143
Stanford University. Presidential Commission on University Budget Priorities.
1.75 Linear feet
Collection is composed of correspondence, questionnaires, minutes, supplementary data, drafts, and final reports from four task forces of the Budget Priorities Commission. Task Force I - Administration and support services; Task Force II - Student support services and activities; Task Force III - Academic calendar and utilization of the Academic plant; Task Force IV - Professorial rank and faculty development. Of note in the records of Task Force II are a report, brochure, and publication of the Black Student Volunteer Center.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers from chairmen of the task forces.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
On October 3, 1974, the University announced the formation of the Presidential Commission on University Budget Priorities. Six task forces were set up to deal with six broad areas of concern: administration and support services, student support services and activities, academic calendar and utilization of the academic plant, professorial rank and faculty development, sponsored research volume, and professional schools and the operating budget. Professors John Linvill, Benjamin Page, Henry Breitrose, Konrad Krauskopf, David Montgomery, and Daniel Bershader headed the task forces.
Description of the Collection
Collection is composed of correspondence, questionnaires, minutes, supplementary data, drafts, and final reports from four task forces of the Budget Priorities Commission. Task Force I - Administration and support services; Task Force II - Student support services and activities; Task Force III - Academic calendar and utilization of the Academic plant; Task Force IV - Professorial rank and faculty development. Of note in the records of Task Force II are a report, brochure, and publication of the Black Student Volunteer Center.
Access Terms
Breitrose, Henry S.; Krauskopf, Konrad Bates, 1910-; Linvill, John G., 1919-2011.; Page, Benjamin M. (Benjamin Markham), 1911-; Stanford University. Black Student Volunteer Center.; Stanford University. Presidential Commission on University Budget Priorities.; Universities and colleges--Administration.
Collection Contents
- Task Force III Academic Calendar and Utilization of he Academic Plant
  - Final Report, Oct. 1, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meeting agendas, notes, abstract of meetings (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence, Feb.-Oct., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty survey responses (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Undergraduate survey responses, nos. 101-259 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Undergraduate survey responses, nos. 260-395 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Supplementary data (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Task Force IV Professorial Rank and Faculty Development
  - Final Report (from Campus Report, Oct. 22, 1975) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - First edition draft (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, April-August 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Summary of replies of department chairmen (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General correspondence, March-July 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General correspondence, Aug. 1975-Jan. 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Task Force II Student Support Services and Activities
  - Final Report, Sept. 29, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Members, formulation, charge (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Agenda (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes and other records, April 4-Sept. 11, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Comments on next-to-last draft (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - AIC, LAC, ODGS [Academic Information Center; Office of Dean of Graduate Studies] (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Athletics, P.E., and Recreation (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chapel, Office of the Dean (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - COSS Report, including questionnaire [Committee on Services to Students] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Counseling and Psych. Services [CAPS] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Counseling - general (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cowell Medical Services (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Financial aids (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Foreign students: Bechtel I-Center (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Job Placement and Career Planning (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minorities, special interest groups (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Professional schools (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Public Events (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Rational for judgments (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Student Affairs, Office of the Dean (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Student organizations, ASSU, etc. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tresidder Memorial Union (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Pre-existing questionnaires and data from students (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - T.F. questionnaires and proposed forum (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Task Force I Administration and Support Services
  - Final Report, Nov. 18, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Task Force Records, April 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Task Force Records, "Indirect Costs," April 28-May 1, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Task Force Records, May-July 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Task Force Records, Aug.-Sept. 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Task Force Records, Oct. 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Task Force Records, Nov. 1975-Jan. 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)